<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on BlitzLiving</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on BlitzLiving</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2017 - Halim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Deliberate Practice and Compounded Growth in Learning</title>
      <link>/posts/deliberate-practice-and-compounded-growth-in-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/deliberate-practice-and-compounded-growth-in-learning/</guid>
      <description>Skill is a result of focussed and consistent practice. When you are learning to improve, the initial rate of skill acquired is usually a flat line.
 A great quote from Ira Glass</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Learning How To Learn</title>
      <link>/posts/learning-how-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/learning-how-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>Notes from the fantastic course on
Learning How To Learn
 1. INTRO/FOCUSED VS. DIFFUSED THINKING  Can only be in one or the other Diffused when writing, write in diffuse mode, edit in focused mode  to engage diffuse brain - before writing, mind-mapping/clustering - take a paper, hold landscape when you write, you want to create new things, think of new relationships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciding What To Build NEXT?</title>
      <link>/startups/deciding-what-to-build-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/startups/deciding-what-to-build-next/</guid>
      <description>Reposted from my original post Medium
Deciding What To Build NEXT? – HelloMeets – Medium Product Managers are an interesting lot. Talk to any PM about their product and they would have a hundreds of different ideas about features they want to add to their product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Avatar
Hey There
I am Halim, a CS graduate turned PM, I love brainstorming new ideas, bringing people together and getting stuff done.
I have a strong interest in system design, cryptocurrencies, Decentralization and the future of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Signature and Public Key Cryptography</title>
      <link>/code/public-key-cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/code/public-key-cryptography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;digital-signature&#34;&gt;Digital Signature&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like a written signature of a document, but it&amp;rsquo;s in digital form. The desired features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only you can sign your own signature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone can verify your signature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A signature is tied to a certain document, it can&amp;rsquo;t be copied and used with other documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BlockGiving- A decentralized giving network</title>
      <link>/programming/blockgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming/blockgiving/</guid>
      <description>Colony Hackathon Submission A decentalized, self-perpuating, cross-border giving network on top of COLONY Project Description This project now lives at Github
Goal: To create a self-perpetuating, decentralized, cross-borders, Giving Platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a scalabale content crawler with a dashboard</title>
      <link>/programming/content-crawler-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming/content-crawler-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>Goals:  To create a comprehensive repository of blogposts from multiple sources. Shorten time required to find relevant items to post read and search. To provide our users a steady stream of content relevant to the Interests &amp;amp; Topics selected by them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>